# Jayasurya Dhanasekaran

## **CLOUD And DEVOPS ENGINEER**

**Address** 217 Mahatma N Sivanandhapuram, Coimbatore, TN, 641035 **Phone** (822) 0996690

E-mail Jayasurya8294@gmail.com

Experienced 6 months as Cloud INFRA Engineer (Oracle Cloud) in PHOENIX Digital technology (WFH), Dubai and 2.8 years as AWS DEVOPS ENGINEERING and 3.6 years as Support Engineer in TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in the organization.

# **Professional Summary**

- 6 months as Cloud INFRA Engineer in OCI (Oracle Cloud Infrastructure), Maintaining and monitoring the end-to-end infrastructure to ensure with 100% availability of all services like Instances, VCN, Load balancers, Attached volumes backups, Database Instances.
- Configured Alerts for CPU, Memory, Disk utilization in OCI console. and worked in load balancer networking. And configured the firewall and port to restrict the unauthorized users to control the traffic at VCN and Server level, and in configured the SSL certificate in Load balancer to change from HTTP to HTTPS protocol.
- Worked as Administrator in Zabbix monitoring Tool with installing the agent in the worker nodes to monitor and configuring the alerts with different available metrics for CPU, Memory and Disk and IOPS to ensure the availability of all running services in the OCI console.
- Managed VCN by creating the Local peering and established a secure connection to Between different Tenancies.
- Scaled up the compute and Block volume and DB instances on the PROD Environment.
- Scheduling an Automatic Backup of PROD and DB server and attached Boot and Block Volume.
- Over 2.8 years of Experience in AWS and DevOps with an applying Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery.
- Excellent skills in applying Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment and Continuous Delivery processes & tools [Example: Git, Maven, Jenkins, Docker, etc.].
- Worked on Jenkins by installing, configuring and maintaining for the purpose of continuous integration (CI) and for End-to-End automation for all build and deployments.
- Used Ansible for Configuration Management.

- Managed GitHub repositories and permissions, including branching and tagging.
- Excellent working knowledge on various virtual systems/ like Docker technologies.
- Containerizing applications with Docker. Responsible for managing the Docker private registry and having good knowledge of maintaining containers using Docker swarm.
- Having Good experience in Amazon Web Services environment and good knowledge of AWS services like Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Elastic Load Balancers, S3, Cloud Front, RDS, VPC, Route53, Cloud watch, Cloud Formation.
- Mainly Concentrated on: EC2 (ELB, AUTO SCALING, EBS), VPC, IAM
   Utilized Cloud Watch to monitor resources such as EC2, CPU memory,
   EB volumes; to set alarms for notification or automated actions; and to monitor logs for a better understanding and operation of the system.
- Actively manage, improve, and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS,
   EC2 including backups, patches, and scaling.
- Worked at optimizing volumes and EC2 instances and created multiple VPC'S
- Implementation of NAT gateways for web apps hosted in private subnets.
- Setup and configured EIP to EC2 instances.
- Created Alarms and notifications for EC2 instances using Cloud Watch.
- Designing and Deploying Highly scalable infrastructure using ELB and Auto Scaling services.
- Setup and managed security groups, VPC specific to environment.
- Creating S3 buckets and also managing policies for S3 buckets and Utilized S3 bucket and Glacier for storage and backup on AWS.
- Created AMI images of critical ec2 instances as backup using AWS CLI and GUI.
- Utilize EBS to store persistent data and mitigate failure by using snapshots

## **Work History**

# 2022 - 07 – current Cloud INFRA Engineer at PHOENIX Digital Technology, Dubai (Remotely working)

- 6 months as Cloud INFRA Engineer in OCI (Oracle Cloud Infrastructure), Maintaining and monitoring the end-to-end infrastructure to ensure with 100% availability of all services like Instances, VCN, Load balancers, Attached volumes backups, Database Instances.
- Configured Alerts for CPU, Memory, Disk utilization in OCI console.
   and worked in load balancer networking. And configured the firewall and port to restrict the unauthorized users to control the traffic at

- VCN and Server level, and in configured the SSL certificate in Load balancer to change from HTTP to HTTPS protocol.
- Worked as Administrator in Zabbix monitoring Tool with installing the
  agent in the worker nodes to monitor and configuring the alerts with
  different available metrics for CPU, Memory and Disk and IOPS to
  ensure the availability of all running services in the OCI console.
- Managed VCN by creating the Local peering and established a secure connection to Between different Tenancies.
- Scaled up the compute and Block volume and DB instances on the PROD Environment.
- Scheduling an Automatic Backup of PROD and DB server and attached Boot and Block Volume.

# 2019 -09 – 2022 -06 **Project 2 - (AWS DevOps Engineer) TCS**

#### Insurance Domain

- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment
- Actively manage, improve, and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2
- including backups, patches, and scaling.
- Used Ansible for Configuration Management
- Automated build and deployment using Jenkins to reduce human error and speed up production processes.
- Managed GitHub repositories and permissions, including branching and tagging.
- Containerizing applications with Docker. Responsible for managing the Docker
- Worked on Kubernetes by creating a Cluster using KOPS methodology,
   POD, Daemon set, replica set, Deployment, Ingress, secrets.
- private registry and having good knowledge of maintaining containers using Docker swarm.
- Worked on Ansible to perform task on the worker node.
- Basic exposure of Python Technologies
- Works on AWS Services but Mainly Concentrated on: EC2 (ELB, AUTO SCALING EBS), VPC, IAM.
- Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets; make connection between different zones; blocking suspicious ip/subnet via ACL.
- Setup/Managing CDN on Amazon Cloud Front to improve site performance. Creating/Managing AMI/Snapshots/Volumes, Upgrade/downgrade AWS resources (CPU, Memory, EBS).
- Utilized Cloud Watch to monitor resources such as EC2, CPU memory,
   EBS volumes; to set alarms for notification or automated actions; and
   to monitor logs for a better understanding and operation of the system

# 2015-08 - 2019-04 **Project 1- (Support Engineer) TCS**

#### Retail Domain

- Worked as Salesforce administrator (Operations) for the client Experience in Control M administration such as monitoring, scheduling, and recovering production batch jobs & ETL load.
- Automated the Mainframes batch jobs to send application status alerts and created dashboards for real time application monitoring.
- Identified bottlenecks and Improved performance of the batch jobs by reducing the run time by 80%
- Worked on Service-now Incident management, Event management, Problem management and Change management

### Certification

### ORACLE certification in Associate oracle cloud

#### infrastructure Foundations.

### **Skills**

#### **Cloud Providers**

AWS and OCI (Oracle Cloud Infrastructure

### **DevOps Tools**

GIT

**JENKINS** 

**ANSIBLE** 

Kubernetes

**DOCKER** 

**SPLUNK** 

LINUX BASIC

**ZABBIX** 

## **Ticketing Tools**

ServiceNow IVANTI

## **Education**

2012-06 - 2015-05 - Bachelor of commerce in Computer Application at *CMS collage of science and commerce, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu - 641049* 

## Languages

English Excellent

Tamil Excellent

Malayalam Very Good

Kannada Good